Now that our data is in good shape,
处理数据的形状之后
we need to get it into the proper form to pass it into our network.
我们需要调整数据并传入网络中
With the skip-gram architecture for each word in the text,
在对于文本中的每个字词使用 skip-gram 结构时
we want to define a surrounding context and grab all the words in
我们都需要定义上下文窗口（大小为 C）
a window around that word with size C. When I talk about a window,
然后获取窗口中的所有字词
I mean a window in time.
窗口是指时间窗口
So, like two words in the past and two words in the future from our given input word.
例如给定输入字词的前两个字词和后两个字词
More generally than two words in the past and future,
我将窗口大小定义为 C
I'm going to say we want to define a window of size C. Here,
而不是具体的前两个字词和后两个字词
I have some text from the Mikolov paper on Word2Vec,
下面这段话摘自 Mikolov 的 Word2Vec 论文
"Since the more distant words are usually less
"Since the more distant words are usually less
related to the current word than those close to it,
related to the current word than those close to it,
we give less weight to the distant words by sampling
we give less weight to the distant words by sampling
less from those words in our training examples.
less from those words in our training examples.
If we choose C equals five,
If we choose C = 5,
for each training word,
for each training word,
we'll randomly select a number R in range one to C,
we'll randomly select a number R in range [1 : C],
and then use R words from history and R words
and then use R words from history and R words
from the future of the current word as correct labels."
from the future of the current word as correct labels."
So, this is saying that we don't want to choose too big of
这段话的意思是我们不能选择太大的窗口
a window because too big of a window will give us irrelevant context.
因为窗口太大的话 上下文就不相关了
In other words, good context words are usually
换句话说 好的上下文字词通常是
the ones closest to the current word rather than farther away,
最靠近当前字词的字词 而不是离得很远的字词
and we want to include some randomness in how we define our context.
我们在定义上下文时 希望引入随机性
If we define a context window of size C equals five,
如果将上下文窗口的大小 C 设为 5
then we'll create a range R that's going to be a random integer between one or five.
那么我们将创建一个范围 R 它是从 1 到 5 的随机整数
So, say we get an R equal to two as an example,
假设 R = 2
then we'll define the context around a given word to be
那么上下文是
the two words that appear right before and after our word of interest.
目标字词前后的两个字词
I have an example here.
举个例子
Say we're interested in the word at the second index in this list, 741.
假设我对这个列表中索引 2处的数字 741 感兴趣
If we randomly generate an R equal to two,
如果 R 随机设为 2
we'll be interested in the two tokens before and after this word.
那么我们将获取该数字前后的两个标记
I want you to write a function that will return context words in a list like this.
请写一个函数 该函数需要返回这样的上下文字词列表
This will be the function get_target,
该函数叫做 get_target()
which takes in a list of word IDs,
输入参数为字词 ID 列表
and index of interests,
目标字词的索引
and a context window size.
以及上下文窗口的大小
So, the effect of getting words within a random rage R instead of a consistent
如果从随机范围 R 中获取字词
larger range C is that you're more
而不是从更大的范围 C 中获取字词
likely to get words that are right next to your current word,
那么更有可能获得紧挨当前字词的字词
and less likely to get words that are further away from your current word.
并且不太可能获得离当前字词很远的字词
So, what you're really doing is going to be training on context words that are
这样我们就有机会使用更靠近目标字词的上下文字词训练网络
closer to your word of interests and likely more relevant, more often.
这些字词很有可能与当前字词关系更紧密
So here, I've left this function for you to fill out.
你需要编写这个函数
Now, there are some special cases.
请注意几个特殊情况
If the index that's passed in is zero or
如果传入的索引是 0
your range cannot go back in the past as far as you want,
或者往前数的字词数量不够
then you can start your context at the start of the past and list of words.
那么上下文可以从传入字词列表的开头开始
You can test out your implementation in this cell below.
你可以在这个单元格中测试你的实现代码
Next, we'll use this function to actually batch the data,
接下来我们将使用该函数批处理数据
and so it's important that this is implemented correctly.
因此一定要正确实现该函数哟
As usual, if you're stuck or want to see my solution,
如果遇到问题或想参考答案
checkout my solution video next.
请观看下个视频